CONTACT

FAISAL NAZAR

@ faizalnazar@outlook.com



PMRA-265 "Shahnas" Anugraha Nagar Manikomvilakom Poonthura P.O Thiruvananthapuram-695026



OBJECTIVE

An Experienced and dedicated Candidtate having degree in Bachelor's of Commerce with Hands on Experience of more than 2 and a half years in Accounting department and Inventory management and also certified by the International Association of Bookkeepers (IAB). Being actively involved in the field of Accounting, Statutory compliance and inventories, I have gained wide experience, which has benefited me professionally and broadened my creative and logical thinking. Looking forward to utilize my full abilities to the better development of both my employer and my career.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth : 30/12/1998
 Marital Status : Single
 Nationality : Indian
 Guardian's Name : S.A Nazar

EXPERIENCE

June 2020 - Present

Jihas & Associates

Financial Accountant

- Preparation of VAT reports
- •Filing VAT returns (Have undergone practical training in GCC VAT returns)
- Inventory management
- · Preparation of GST reports
- GST Filing
- · Maintaining Profit & Loss Account
- Preparation of Balance Sheet
- · Bank and GST Reconciliation
- Auditing
- Well versed in Tally prime
- Preparing Monthly statements by analyzing relevant data
- Prepares Quartlerly and Annual Financials
- Preparing Budgets ,and Forecasting
- · Maintaining and Analyzing Cash flow Statement
- Completion of the monthly accruals, journals, fixed assets and depreciation schedules
- · Training and guiding Junior Staffs
- Studies current and new legislation to ensure compliance with federal, state, and local financial regulations
- Collects and examines account information necessary to reconcile financial discrepancies
- Verifies documentation, requests expenditures, and prepares disbursements
- Ensures client confidentiality by keeping financial information secure
- Regular reports and statistics will be presented before the senior management team when required

1 Dec 2018 - 29th Feb 2020

MOBILE POINT - Mobile sales and Service

Accounts Assistant

- · Preparing Daily report
- · Assisting finance manager in Final accounts preparation
- · inventory Management
- Preparing Accounting data for GST filing
- · Handling purchase and Sales invoices
- Preparing Tax Incoices
- · Preparing Proforma Invoice
- · Handling petty cash
- Preparing Daybook
- · Bank reconciliation
- · Well versed in Tally
- · Training and guiding Junior Staffs
- Studies current and new legislation to ensure compliance with federal, state, and local financial regulations
- · Collects and examines account information necessary to reconcile financial discrepancies
- · Verifies documentation, requests expenditures, and prepares disbursements
- Ensures client confidentiality by keeping financial information secure
- Regular reports and statistics will be presented before the senior management team when required

01 May 2018 - 31 Nov 2018

MOBILE POINT - Mobile sales and Service

Accounts Trainee

- · Preparing Daily Report
- · Inventory management
- · Handling Sales and Purchase invoices

EDUCATION

2019

Kerala University

M.Com

Currently pursuing

2019 • Kerala University

B.Com Taxation

2016 • Christ Nagar Senior Secondary school (CBSE)

Plus two

2019
• G-Tec centre for computer studies

International Association of Bookkeepers (IAB) Certified

Grade A

2019
• G-Tec Centre for Computer studies

Professional Diploma in Indian and Foreign Accounting and SAP accounting

Grade A

2019
• G-Tec Centre for computer studies

SAP KA Certified

Grade A

ARTICLE PUBLICATION

Women Entrepreneurship

An article titled "Women entrepreneurship" was presented at the One day National conference regarding 'The Emergence of Start-Up Eco system in India' Organised by Indo Asian Academy group of Institutions. The Artice was then later published by KAAV publications, National Journal of Arts, Commerce and Scientific Research Review (NJACSRR).

SKILLS

- · Teaching and Presentation Skills
- Good verbal and written English Communication
- · Adaptive In nature
- Flexible timing
- · Well Versed in Tally Prime

 Mentoring and Guiding Juniors IAB Certified SAP certified • Versed in Usage of Quickbooks online • Experienced in Handling MS Excel and Word LANGUAGE -• English (Read, Write and Speak) • Malayalam (Read, Write & Speak) Hindi (Read and Write only) REFERENCE -• Zakeer Hussain - "Mobile Point" Branch Manager Mobile.point5@gmail.com +917012548717 Jihas M - "Jihas & Associates" **Chartered Accountant** Jihasassociates@gmail.com +919809103313 **HOBBIES** Travelling Playing Badminton **Playing Cricket** Listening Music

• I hereby Declare that The above furnished details are true to the best of my knowledge and belief

DECLARATION